A Guide to the Collection of Microfilmed William Faulkner Exhibit Materials
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Collection of Microfilmed William Faulkner Exhibit Materials ca. 1931-1951
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6084
ca. 230 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the Library's microfilms of the William Faulkner manuscripts in its custody; the microfilm may be consulted by any interested party, and it will be lent through the interlibrary loan system. Materials are constantly added. Long-term loans may be arranged. Use of the microfilm will be restricted to the premises of the borrowing library. No loans will be made to individuals. Researchers should enquire of the Manuscripts Division concerning availability of microfilm of manuscripts that are pertinent to their work. Most of the literary manuscripts in our collections written by Faulkner, both holograph and typescript, have also been published in facsimile in William Faulkner Manuscripts, 25 vols (New York: Garland, 1986-87).
By the terms of the agreement by which the William Faulkner Foundation transferred the original manuscripts to the University, access to the original manuscripts is restricted (to ensure the survival of the physically-delicate originals) to doctoral candidates at the dissertation stage of their programs, and to certain mature scholars and critics. But even these researchers must demonstrate need to see the originals that goes beyond the requirements of most routine research. A doctoral candidate at the dissertation stage, or other qualified researcher who believes that his or her work requires access to the originals must correspond with the Curator of Manuscripts prior to arrival at the Library to obtain permission for access.
No microfilm, electrostatic, or other types of copies may be made of materials written by William Faulkner that are in our William Faulkner Collections. Other materials in the collections may be copied subject to the normal rules of the Library established under the conditions of the Copyright Act. All copying is performed by the Printing Services Department of the University.
Acquisition Information
Deposited in the Manuscripts Department 6 July 1959, by Kenneth Godfrey of New York. N.Y. for an exhibit. Selected items were microfilmed, and the originals returned to Mr. Godfrey.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of microfilm of selected materials loaned to the University of Virginia Library for an exhibit on William Faulkner.
Organization
The listing is compiled in the order in which items appear on the microfilm reel.
Contents List
- Papers
  - Lewis Gannett on Light in August, 1932 10/6 (?); Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - 72 publishers note cards containing autograph bibliographical descriptions of specific editions of Faulkner's works, n. d.; Note cards
  - 26 typed sheets containing publisher's bibliographical descriptions of specific editions of Faulkner's works, n. d.; Typed sheets
  - Recapitulation of Sales for... Jonathan Cape and Harrison Smith, 1931 Feb, Apr; Misc. 9 sheets
  - Correspondence between Linton Massey and Kenneth Godfrey, 1957 Sep 26 -1958 Oct 4; TLS 6 letters
  - First 4 leaves of sixth printing of Sanctuary, [1931 Jul]; Photostats 2 items
  - Linton Massey 's article for The Virginia Librarian (Vol. II, No. 4), Bibliographia Virginia or Ledgermania, [1955-1956]; Printed article2 p.
  - The Publisher's Weekly, 1931 Oct 3; Pamphlet 4 p.
  - The Publisher's Weekly, 1931 Aug 15; Pamphlet 3 p.
  - Slavery Better for the Negro, Says Faulkner, from New York Herald Tribune, 1931 Nov 14; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - William Faulkner Literary White Hope from Mississippi, Likens Himself in City to a 'Houn' Dawg Under a Wagon,' from New York World Telegram, 1931 Nov 4; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - "Book Marks for Today", n. d.; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - Reading and Writing, Up From Mississippi(from McCall's), 1931 Jul; Magazine clipping 2 p.
  - A Chamber of Horrors, review of Sanctuary from New York Sun, [1931] Feb 13; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - A Ricky Sinister and Furious Novel, from New York Herald Tribune, 1932 Oct 9; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - Tarnished Angels, n. d.; Movie review 1 p.
  - The Sound and The Fury, 1959 Mar 3; Movie review 1 p.
  - Spring Announcements, Harrison Smith, Inc., 1932; Pamphlet 3 p.
    includes 2 page article on Light in August
  - Infatuation with Sound of Own Words Department, from New Yorker, [1940 May 2]; Magazine article 1 p.
  - Review of The Hamlet from The First Reader, n. d.; Magazine review 1 p.
  - Road to Glory, from Script, [1936 Aug]; Magazine review 1 p.
  - Review of The Unvanquished from New York World Telegram, n. d.; Magazine review 1 p.
  - "The Faulkner Mixture: Light in August," from New York Sun, 1932 Oct 7; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - Review of The Unvanquished, n. d.; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - Review of Absalom, Absalom from New York World Telegram, 1936 Oct 26; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - Review Pylon from New York World Telegram, 1935 Mar 27; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - Review of The Bear Hunt, from New York World Telegram, 1934 Feb 17; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - Announcement of sale of Christmas Tree, 1936 Jan 17; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - From the Naborhood Theater Guide regarding William Faulkner's part in screenplay for Sutter's Gold, 1934 Aug 11; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - A Miscellany of Faulkner Stories, from New York Herald Tribune, 1934 Apr 15; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - Review of Sanctuary, from the New York Sun, 1931 Mar 24; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - Review of Absalom, Absalom! from Newsweek, 1936 Oct 31; Magazine review 1 p.
  - Review mentioning William Faulkner from New York World Tribune, 1934 Feb 19; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - Faulkner's Barn Burning Wins a First, from New York World Tribune, 1939 Nov 17; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - Review of Pylon from New York Herald Tribune, 1935 Mar 25; Newspaper clipping
  - Review of The Wild Palms from New York Herald Tribune, n. d.; Newspaper clipping
  - Review of Dr. Martino from New York World Telegram, 1934 Apr 16; Newspaper clipping
  - Review of Absalom, Absalom! from New York Sun, 1936 Oct 30; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - Review of The Wild Palms from New York World Telegram, 1936(?) Jan; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - Autograph notes concerning various editions of William Faulkner's Sanctuary, n. d.; Notes 6 p.
  - Excerpt from Carvel Collins' Interior Monologues[?], n. d.; Excerpt 1 p.
  - Evelyn Harter Glick to Ken [Godfrey]?, 1955 Oct 17; TLS 1 p.
  - Linton Massey to Kenneth Godfrey, 1955 May 20; TLS 1 p.
  - [Kenneth Godfrey] to Linton Massey, 1955 Nov 3; TL 2 p.
  - [ Kenneth Godfrey] to Evelyn Glick, 1955 Nov 3; TL 2 p.
  - Checklists of Twentieth Century Authors, n. d.; Pamphlets 3 p.
  - Paul Romaine of Cassanova to Cape & Smith Publishers, 1931 May 25; TLS 1 p.
  - Cape & Smith Inc. to Paul Romaine, 1931 Jun 1; TL 1 p.
  - "Cassanova" to Kenneth Godfrey, 1931 Jun 4; Telegram 1 p.
  - Cape & Smith to Cassanova, 1931 Jun 5; TL 1 p.
  - Walter J. Robertson at Oxford University Press to Cape & Smith, 1931 Sep 26; TLS 1 p.
  - Dealer's announcement regarding The Lilacs, n. d.; announcement [2 items]
  - Sidney S. Alberts to Kenneth Godfrey, 1931 Nov 7; TLS 1 p.
  - [ Kenneth Godfrey] to Sidney S. Alberts, 1931 Nov 11; TL 1 p.
  - Sidney S. Alberts to Kenneth Godfrey, 1931 Jul 18; TLS 1 p.
  - [ Kenneth Godfrey] to Sidney S. Alberts, 1931 Jul 20; TL 1 p.
  - Sidney S. Alberts to Cape & Smith, 1931 May 29; TLS 1 p.
  - unknown to Sidney S. Alberts, 1931 Jun 5; TL 2 p.
  - Paul Romaine to Kenneth Godfrey, 1931 Nov 6; TLS 2 p.
  - Cape & Smith to Paul Romaine, 1931 Nov 27; TL 3 p.
  - H. W. Schwartz of Cassanova to Kenneth Godfrey, 1931 Oct 29; TL 2 p.
  - Kenneth Godfrey to H. W. Schwartz, 1931 Nov 4; TL 2 p.
  - Kenneth Godfrey to H. W. Schwartz, 1931 Oct 26; TL 1 p.
  - Few autograph additions to unidentified TMS listing of Faulkner's Works, n. d.; Catalogue listing 2 p.
  - Catalogue of Cassanova's First Editions; includes William Faulkner, n. d.; Pamphlet 4 p.
  - Pelican Book Shop to Kenneth Godfrey, 1931 Jul 23; TL 2 p.
  - [ Kenneth Godfrey] to Pelican Book Shop, 1931 Jul 30; TL 1 p.
  - [ Kenneth Godfrey] to Pelican Book Shop, 1931 Jul 15; TL 1 p.
  - Pelican Book Shop to Kenneth Godfrey, 1931 Aug 19; TL 1 p.
  - [ Kenneth Godfrey] to Miss Ivey Cordell of Pelican Book Shop, 1931 Aug 24; TL 1 p.
  - Pelican Book Shop to Kenneth Godfrey, 1931 Jul 18; TL 1 p.
  - [ Kenneth Godfrey] to Pelican Book Shop, 19[31?] Jul 20; TL 1 p.
  - [ Kenneth Godfrey] to Pelican Book Shop, 1931 Aug 7; TL 1 p.
  - Pelican Book Shop to Kenneth Godfrey, 1931 Jul 12; TL 1 p.
  - Kenneth Godfrey to Pelican Book Shop, 1931 Jun 13; TL 1 p.
  - Pelican Book Shop to Kenneth Godfrey, 1931 May 11; TL 1 p.
  - [ Kenneth Godfrey] to Pelican Book Shop, 1931 May 20; TL 1 p.
  - Pelican Book Shop to Kenneth Godfrey, 1931 May 27; TL 1 p.
  - unknown to Pelican Book Shop, 1931 Jun 8; TL 1 p.
  - Pelican Book Shop to Kenneth Godfrey, 1931 May 20; TL 2 p.
  - Pelican Book Shop to Kenneth Godfrey, 1931 May 8; TL 2 p.
  - [ Kenneth Godfrey] to Pelican Book Shop, 1931 May 12; TL 2 p.
  - Pelican Book Shop to Kenneth Godfrey, 1931 May 4; TL 2 p.
  - [ Kenneth Godfrey] to Pelican Book Shop, 1931 May 8; TL 3 p.
  - Pelican Book Shop to Kenneth Godfrey, 1931 Apr 27; TL 1 p.
  - [ Kenneth Godfrey] to Pelican Book Shop, 1931 May 5; TL 2 p.
  - Pelican Book Shop to Cape & Smith, 1931 Apr 23; TL 1 p.
  - [ Kenneth Godfrey] to Pelican Book Shop, 1931 Apr 29; TL 2 p.
  - Kenneth Godfrey to Pelican Book Shop, 1931 Apr 24; TL 1 p.
  - New Yorker story on William Faulkner with Commins, 1953 Feb 28; Magazine article 2 p.
  - Our Literature Came of Age, from New York Times Book Review, n. d.; Book review 3 p.
  - "T. V.: Faulkner's Sound and Fury," from New York Times, 1955 Dec 7; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - Faulkner Novel Sets T. V. High, from Chicago Daily News, 1955 Dec 6; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - Cutting of Faulkner Reduces Big Impact, from Billboard, 1955 Dec 7; Newsclipping 1 p.
  - Faulkner, from Long Island Star Journal, 1955 May 12; Newsclipping 1 p.
  - "Faulkner Requiem Click in a Preem in Zurich,"f from Variety, 1955 Oct 26; Newsclipping 1 p.
  - Review of Requiem For a Nun, from Time, 1951 Sep 24; Magazine review 2 p.
  - "What French Readers Find in William Faulkner's Fiction", Magazine article 1 p.
  - Review of Intruder in the Dust from New York Times, Sep 27; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - Review of Requiem For a Nun from New York Times Book Review, 1951 Sep 30; Newsclipping 2 p.
  - William Faulkner's Enduring Power, from New York Times Book Review, 1954 Apr 4; Newsclipping 2 p.
  - Review of The Private World of William Faulkner from New York Times Book Review, n. d.; Newsclipping 1 p.
  - Review of A Fable, 1954 Aug 2; Newsclipping 1 p.
  - Review of War and Peace and Mr. Faulkner from New York Times Book Review, 1954 Aug 1; Newsclipping 2 p.
  - Review of Go Down, Moses, n. d.; Newsclipping 1 p.
  - Movies and the Negro, from New York Times, 1949 Nov 25; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - Movie review of Intruder in the Dust from Variety, 1949 Oct 12; Newsclipping 1 p.
  - Review of Collected Stories of William Faulkner, from Time, 1950 Aug 28; Magazine review 1 p.
  - Faulkner in Hollywood, from New York Sun, 1932 Sep 3; Newspaper clipping 2 p.
  - Cape & Smith List of Books to be Published, [1930]; Pamphlet 6 p.
  - Review of These Thirteen, n. d.; Newsclipping 1 p.
  - Review of Sanctuary, 1931 Feb 10; Newsclipping 1 p.
  - Today's Author: William Faulkner, from New York World Telegram, 1931 Sep 23; Newsclipping 1 p.
  - Review These Thirteen, from New York Herald Tribune, 1931 Sep 22; Newspaper clipping 2 p.
  - Review of Sanctuary from New York World Telegram, 1932 Mar 22; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - Review of Sanctuary from Times Literary Supplement, 1931 Sep 24; Newsclipping 1 p.
  - Review of Spotted Horses, from New York World Telegram, 1931 Jun 2; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - Review of Sanctuary from The Observer, 1931 Sep 20; Newsclipping 1 p.
  - Review of Sanctuary from New York World Telegram, 1931 Feb 17; Newspaper clipping 1 p.
  - Review of Sanctuary from The Daily Telegram, 1931 Oct 2; Newspaper clipping 1 p.